Guide to the Mountain Fuel Supply Company audio-visual collection 1968-1979
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Mountain Fuel Supply Company audio-visual collection
1968-1979
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0314
Mountain Fuel Supply Company
57 16mm films, 7 reel-to-reel audiotapes, 2 phonograph records, 2 audiocassette, and 1 2-inch videotape.
The Mountain Fuel Supply Company audio-visual collection (1968-1979) consists of films promoting the use of natural gas and documenting the production and transmission of natural gas and sound recordings of speeches and interviews relating to natural gas production. The collection also contains some employee training films. Mountain Fuel Supply was an oil and gas energy company based in Salt Lake City, Utah. The company was reoragnized in 1984 to form Questar Corporation.
Organizational History
Mountain Fuel Supply Company began life in 1928 as the oil and gas exploration and production division of Western Public Service Corporation, a Salt Lake City holding company which served the Salt Lake Valley with natural gas from northern Utah and southwestern Wyoming. In 1935 shareholders consolidated Western Public Service Corporation into a single company called Mountain Fuel Supply Company. Shareholders returned to the holding company structure in 1984 and reorganized the company to form Questar Corporation.
The Mountain Fuel Supply Company audio-visual collection (1968-1979) consists of films promoting the use of natural gas and documenting the production and transmission of natural gas and sound recordings of speeches and interviews relating to natural gas production. The collection also contains some employee training films.
The materials are arranged by format and by the order in which they were added to the collection. Items 1-31 comprise the original collection while items 32-51 and 52-67 were accessioned in 1997 and 2002, respectively.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
Questar Corporation; Gas distribution--West (U.S.)--History--Sources; Natural gas--West (U.S.); Public Utilities; Moving Images; Sound Recordings; Moving images; Sound recordings
- 1988 donation
  - Green River broadcast, June 09; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 1)
  - Newcomer Society speech, 1968 March 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 2)
    Featuring W.T. Nightngale, chairman of the board
  - Conversation with William, 1973 August 22; Audiocassette (Cassette 3)
    Conversations with William "Bill" Utzinger at age 75. In 1928-1929 he strung a gas pipe between Rock Springs, Wyoming and Salt Lake City, Utah.
  - 1968 Gas range campaign, 1968 August 22; Phonograph record (Disc 4)
  - Unidentified record, undated; Phonograph record (Disc 5)
    Disc
  - "Pipeline in the Rockies", undated; 16mm film (Reel 6)
  - "Natural Gas: Energy in the Home", undated; 16mm film (Reel 7)
  - American Gas Association, undated; 16mm film (Reel 8)
    Presentation of "One Chance"
  - "Vital Link", undated; 16mm film (Reel 9)
  - "The Energy Challenge", undated; 16mm film (Reel 10)
  - "Eternal Flame", undated; 16mm film (Reel 11)
  - "Journey to Total Energy", undated; 16mm film (Reel 12)
  - "Geology and Natural Gas", undated; 16mm film (Reel 13)
  - "Jet Age American Gas", undated; 16mm film (Reel 14)
  - "Physical and Chemical Properties of Natural Gas", undated; 16mm film (Reel 15)
  - "Heating and Refrigeration Show", undated; 16mm film (Reel 16)
  - Old pipeline, undated; 16mm film (Reel 17)
  - "Natural Gas and You", undated; 16mm film (Reel 18)
  - "The Other Side of the Street", undated; 16mm film (Reel 19)
  - "Natural Gas", undated; 16mm film (Reel 20)
  - "Energy 2000: An Exclusive Enviromental Color Report", undated; 16mm film (Reel 21)
  - "The Story of Natural Gas", undated; 16mm film (Reel 22)
  - "Energy/Scope Revisited" part 1, undated; 16mm film (Reel 23)
  - "Energy/Scope Revisited" part 2, undated; 16mm film (Reel 24)
    MoFilm The next four films are black and white. A note enclosed with them indicates that these films have shrunk with age and will probably not run in a projector without damage.
  - "Pipeline 29", undated; 16mm film Black and white (Reel 25)
    This item has experienced shrinkage and will not run in a projector without damage to the film.
  - "Pipeline in the Rockies" reel A, undated; 16mm film Black and white (Reel 26)
  - "Pipeline in the Rockies" reel B, undated; 16mm film Black and white (Reel 27)
  - "Pipeline in the Rockies" soundtrack, undated; 16mm film (Reel 28)
  - "Pipeline in the Rockies" A and B rolls and soundtrack, undated; 16mm film (Reel 29)
  - Outtakes, undated; 16mm film (Reel 30)
    A series of outtakes beginning with the 20th Century Fox theme music.
  - Mountain Fuel Supply Phil Riesen outtakes, 1979 February 23; 16mm film (Reel 31)
- 1997 addendum
  - "The Ego Trap", undated; 16mm film (Reel 32)
  - "You Pack Your Own Chute", undated; 16mm film (Reel 33)
  - "Pipeline 29", undated; 16mm film (Reel 34)
  - "Pipeline 29", undated; 16mm film (Reel 35)
  - "Pipeline 29", undated; 16mm film (Reel 36)
  - "Pipeline 29", undated; 16mm film (Reel 37)
  - "Pipeline 29", undated; 16mm film (Reel 38)
  - "Pipeline 29", undated; 16mm film (Reel 39)
  - "Thanks A-Plenty Boss: The Rewards of Rewarding", undated; 16mm film (Reel 40)
  - "Thanks A-Plenty Boss: The Correct Way of Correcting", undated; 16mm film (Reel 41)
  - "Pipeline in the Rockies", undated; 16mm film (Reel 42)
  - "Pipeline in the Rockies", undated; 16mm film (Reel 43)
  - "Pipeline in the Rockies", undated; 16mm film (Reel 44)
  - "Pipeline in the Rockies", undated; 16mm film (Reel 45)
  - W.T. Nightingale, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 46)
  - Newcomer Society speech, 1963 March 07; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 47)
    W.T. Nightingale, chairman of the board, Mountain Fuel Supply Co.
  - Mountain Fuel Supply Co., M.M. Fidlar, president, 1967 December 20; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 48)
  - Complete meeting of the NYSSA, 1965 March 17; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 49)
    Featuring M.M. Fidlar, president.
  - Monitor: Dr. Simon Ramo, undated; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 50)
  - John Crawford at PGGA market conference, 1975; Audiocassette (Cassette 51)
- 2002 addendum
  - "Easy Energy", undated; 16mm film (Reel 52)
  - "Turning on Energy", undated; 16mm film (Reel 53)
  - "A History of Natural Gas", undated; 16mm film (Reel 54)
  - "Cooking Al Fresco", undated; 16mm film (Reel 55)
  - "Vital Link", undated; 16mm film (Reel 56)
  - "Gas Energy for America", undated; 16mm film (Reel 57)
  - "Pennsylvania Country Cooking", undated; 16mm film (Reel 58)
  - "Pleasures of Chinese Cooking", undated; 16mm film (Reel 59)
  - "Scandinavia", undated; 16mm film (Reel 60)
  - "Cooking of Germany", undated; 16mm film (Reel 61)
  - "Latin American", undated; 16mm film (Reel 62)
  - "Outdoor Cooking", undated; 16mm film (Reel 63)
  - "Pipeline 29", undated; 16mm film (Reel 64)
  - "Laundry Bag", undated; 16mm film (Reel 65)
  - "It All Comes out in the Wash", undated; 16mm film (Reel 66)
  - Harris Lowe's commercial for Mountain Fuel, undated; 2-inch videotape (Reel 67)